"Chair of Pico and Nano Satellites, and Satellite Constellations TUM School of Engineering and Design Technical University"	
of Munich	
Spacecraft Design - Project Description	
The  Spacecraft  Design  project  requires  students  to  examine  a  m1ss1on  statement  and  a	
"description of the mission, and then detail and size the spacecraft subsystems and produce an overall spacecraft design. The students are divided in groups of 6-8 members."	
Topics - Mission Statement	
Finding Plastic Patches in the Pacific Ocean using Optical Satellite Observations	
"""At Ocean Voyages Institute, we recognize the urgent need to address the growing issue of"	
"plastic pollution in our oceans. Our mission is to develop a spacecraft capable of gathering accurate and comprehensive data on plastic concentration in the Pacific Ocean, particularly in identifying plastic clusters."	
We envision a spacecraft equipped with optical instrumentation that can track and map plastic	
"debris, providing us with vital information on the location, and size. With this data, we can gain a deeper understanding of the scale of the problem and develop effective strategies to mitigate"	
its impact.	
"Our goal is to create a spacecraft that can operate with precision and efficiency, covering large"	
areas of the Pacific Ocean to gather the most comprehensive data possible. We believe that this mission will play a critical role in raising awareness of the plastic pollution crisis and catalyzing action to address it.	
"Through our work, we hope to inspire others to join us in the fight against plastic pollution and to"	
"create a cleaner, healthier ocean for generations to come."""	
Parameters	
Orbit	
Initial orbital parameters:	
Parameter	Values
Semimajor axis (a)	6371 + 250 + 10*(Num.Group -1) [km]
Eccentricity (e)	0
Inclination (i)	0
RAAN (0)	0
True anomaly (  )	0
A rgumont ofPerigee( )	0
Resolution	
Grotmd Sampling Di stance (GSD) - 20 + 8 * (	
-1) [m]	
Wavelength selection 1	
NIR wave (A. = 880nm): To distinguish plastic from water.	
-03	
"Blue light (},= 443nm l : To distinguish plastic from:"	
seaweeds timber	
other debris	
005-	
004 -	
1 Seawater	
• S1rg1Ssum seaweed	
• Rafted logs of Timber	
• PlasticTargets	
Sea Foam (spume)	
• Pumice Rock	
-02	
002-	
Figure 1- Remote Sensing Reflectance of sea floatin rials	
001 -	
-01	
I       I         I        I                                                                               I	
•90      560       665      7•0       840                                                                                                                        1610	
Temperature Range: -30 degrees Celsius to 60 deg     §91  (nm)	
Celsius TT&C system	
Losses of the receiving antenna: 3 dB	
1	
"Biermann, L., Clewley, D., Martinez-Vicente, V. et al. Finding Plastic Patches in Coastal Waters using"	
"Optical Satellite Data. Sci Rep 10, 5364 (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-62298-z"	
2	
Antenna perfectly aligned and there are no polarization mismatch losses	
Satellite is on the zenith of the ground station and there are no obstacles or	
atmospheric  losses	
N.B. You have to design a single spacecraft and not more than one. No constellations	
or swarms.	
What to include in the report - Everything must be justified	
"Mission objectives: primary objective, secondary objectives"	
Main requirements	
Technical requirements for each subsystem System Architecture	
o   System	
•	
Mass Budget	
Power Budget	
Link Budget	
o   Mission Orbit & DeltaV	
•	
Orbital parameters of the target orbit	
Ground track of the target orbit	
Sun light and eclipse time	
DeltaV to reach the target orbit	
Deorbit manoeuvre	
o   Propulsion system	
•	
"Type of propulsion system selected with main parameters ( lsp, T)"	
Propellant mass	
o   Launcher selection	
o    Ground Segment:	
•	
Ground station location selection	
o   Spacecraft	
•	
Payload: Optical instrumentation sizing (diameter and focal length)	
•	
AOCS	
•	
Sensors and actuators	
Power Subsystem	
Solar Arrays Size and Mass Battery Size and Mass	
•	
TT&C subsystem	
Frequency band selection Antenna selection	
•	
Structure	
Size of the satellite Material definition	
Configuration/placement  of the subsystems	
•	
Thermal subsystem	
Hot and cold case temperature	
Coating and passive and/or active thermal control instruments	
Info about the report and the presentation	
The examination consists of a report accompanied  by a final presentation.  Grading is	
"based on the  submitted  report,  and a final  presentation  at the  end  of  the  semester serves as a grade modifier."	
•    The presentation has to have a duration of 10 minutes (all the members of the	
"group have to present), followed by a Q&A session."	
•    The report length has to be limited to 15 pages. Each student has to specify the	
personal contribution at the beginning of each paragraph.	
"•    The presentation will occur the last day of lecture, on the 20th of July 2023 ."	
The report has to be delivered within the 30th of July 2023.	
